Guide to the Non-traditional Jewish life in the San Francisco Bay Area: collection of liturgical material
Department of Special Collections
Non-traditional Jewish life in the San Francisco Bay Area: collection of liturgical material
1985-2003
M1412
Kisber, Susie
1 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Printed material, primarily liturgies. Compiled and/or created for feminist, Queer, and multicultural Jewish communities in the San Francisco Bay Area from 1982-2000. Consists of three series: Holidays, Shabbat, and Life Cycle Events.
Access
Collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 24 hours in advance of intended use.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Susie Kisber, 2003. Accession 2003-338.
Biography / Administrative History
Susie Loveman Kisber, born in Atlanta, Georgia in 1965, completed her doctorate in clinical psychology from CSPP in 1999. Publications include her dissertation, A Comparison of Non-parents, Parents, and Prospective Parents Who are Jewish Lesbian, Bisexual, Transgender, and Queer Identified Women: Differences in their Identities, Lifestyle, Families, Social Networks, and Received Social Support; and a chapter in Celebrating the Lives of Jewish Women: Patterns in a Feminist Sampler. In 1995 she co-founded Pardes Rimonim, a Jewish feminist, earth-centered, multicultural ritual community located in the San Francisco Bay Area. She is active in the progressive Queer Jewish community locally and internationally.
Scope and Content of Collection
Printed material, primarily liturgies. Compiled and/or created for feminist, Queer, and multicultural Jewish communities in the San Francisco Bay Area from 1982-2000. Consists of three series: Holidays, Shabbat, and Life Cycle Events.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Kisber, Susie; Gay communities--San Francisco Bay Area; Jewish women; Lesbians; Jewish life in the San Francisco Bay Area
Collection Contents
- Series 1. Holidays, .5 linear ft.
  - Subseries 1. High Holidays (Rosh ha-Shanah and Yom Kipur)
    - Pardes Rimonim machzor, 5756. 1996, Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Pardes Rimonim machzor, undated., Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 2. Sukot
    - Pardes Rimonim, Celebration honoring the harvest, undated., Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Ushpezin/Invitation to the mothers in the sukah.1992, Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Songsheet, undated., Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Women and sukot: may our homes be shelters of peace. Jewish Women's Calendar.1994, Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Subseries 3. Tu bi-Shevat
    - Pardes Rimonim Tu B'Shevat seder.1996, Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Pardes Rimonim Tu B'Shevat seder.1999, Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Susie and Mano's Tu B'Shevat seder.2000, Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 4. Pesah
    - Subsubseries 1. Songs and Poems
      - Pesah songs and poems, undated., Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Subsubseries 2. Hagadot
      - Supplement to the New Union haggadah.1982, Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - The Telling: a loving haggadah for passover.1982, Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Liberation haggadah.1986, Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - A New haggadah: a Jewish lesbian seder.1987, Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Let us begin: a haggadah for Passover.1988, Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Passover-Ramadan liberation.1991, Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Two feminist hagadot.1992, Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Three hagadot.1995, Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - The Cohn Family haggadah.1997, Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Welcome to our (very first, very own) Seder1999, Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Thyme's haggadah draft I, undated., Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - A Haggadah of liberation, undated., Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - Hagadah shel pesah, undated., Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - The stolen legacy: a women's haggadah, undated., Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - The San Diego women's haggadah, 2nd ed., undated., Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Subseries 5. Lag be-Omer
    - Trek through anxiety and hope: counting the omer, undated., Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Series 2. Shabbat, .5 linear ft.
  - Subseries 1. Friday Night Services
    - Jewish Feminist Conference/songs and prayers.1982, Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - A womyn's Friday night service.1982, Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - 12th International conference of gay and lesbian jews: welcoming shabbat.1990, Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Siddur.1993, Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Beth Jacob Congregation kabbalat shabbat.1994, Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Queer solstice shabbat.1994, Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Queer Minyan tu b'shevat shabbat.1995, Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Queer Minyan shabbat: memory and ritual.1995, Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Shabbat evening service, undated., Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Lekhah dodi li-krat kalah, undated., Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - (Queer Minyan) siddur, undated., Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Shabbat shalom, undated., Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Kiddush for Friday night, undated., Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Shabat shalom, undated., Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Kabbalat shabbat, undated., Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Shabat shalom, undated., Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Siddur, undated., Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Songs and prayers, undated., Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - A Taste of honey: siddur, undated., Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - [Queer Minyan] Invitation to the mothers, undated., Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Subseries 2. Morning Prayers
    - SF New Feminist Minyan draft service.1987, Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Queer Minyan shabbat service.1994, Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Queer Minyan.1995, Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Pardes Rimonim shabbat morning prayer book.1996, Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Queer Minyan.1998, Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Subseries 3. Havdalah
    - Celebrating the ancestors of many cultures.1993, Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Jewish Women's Caucus.1995, Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Series 3. Life Cycle Events, 4 folders
  - Subseries 1. Naming Ceremony
    - The naming of Shoshana.1992, Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Subseries 2. Perpetual Engagement Siddur
    - Siddur for Susie and Mano's perpetual engagement weekend, undated., Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Subseries 3. Memorial Life Celebration
    - Dov Ben Hayim.1994, Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Subseries 4. Yahrzeit Ritual
    - In memory of Shoshannah's father Stuart Kisber.1995, Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Summary of Susie Kisber's study done at Stanford in 1995: a needs assessment of GLB Jewish students & young adults on Bay Area college campuses. (3 pp.), Accession no. 2003-338 (Box 2, Folder 32)